

#### MARCEL FAHLE

327 Pavonia Ave, #2 Jersey City, NJ 07302

T 302.983.1416

Profile

I am a Full Stack Developer with fifteen years of experience in both front- and backend-development. In recent years my main focus and passion lies in Ruby, HTML5 and JavaScript. m.fahle@gmail.com http://marcelfahle.net http://github.com/marcelfahle http://twitter.com/marcelfahle

You can find some of my work in my Portfolio or on Github at: http://github.com/marcelfahle

Experience

Chief Technology Officer, Jumblzar, Hoboken, NJ – 01/2013 - Present

Jumblzar is a marketplace for baby and kids items. I am lead architect/developer of the Ruby based platform.

## Freelance / Contract Web Developer - 07/2006-Present

Since 2006 I have worked with various clients, often as a subcontracter for internet and advertising agencies, to create web applications in a wide range of industries. The following list contains clients I work with on a regular basis:

## Very Memorable, New York, NY

- Worked on multiple client projects including PBS Kids and 1938Media, featuring HTML5 Canvas Animation, JavaScript and Ruby.

#### Gedankenwerk, Essen, Germany

- Worked as lead developer on dozens of projects for Deutsche Telekom, Nokia, ThyssenKrupp and others.
- I did the entire frontend development of smart's 2010 international campaign "the smart class" in colaboration with BBDO Proximity
- Served as project manager for Deutsche Telekom's Intranet Relaunch "You and me"
- Co-architected the video streaming infrastructure for Deutsche Telekom's Intranet worldwide and developed the systems to manage the video content
- Technologies include: Ruby, Ruby on Rails, RSpec, Cucumber, PostgreSQL, MySQL, JavaScript, CoffeScript, HTML5, Heroku, AWS, Wordpress, PHP, Flash AS3, Flex

# 9elements.com, Bochum, Germany

- I worked on multiple applications with 9elements including img.ly, a photosharing app for twitter.
- Technologies include: Ruby, Ruby on Rails, RSpec, Cucumber, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Sinatra as well as Flash and PHP before 2009

FDT Platform Evangelist, Powerflasher, Aachen, Germany - 03/2008-11/2008

With Powerflasher I traveled to various conferences around the globe to spread the love about FDT, the Flash development IDE.

Web Developer, MAT-Computing, Bochum, Germany - 08/1998-10/2006

As the only web developer I was responsible for creating interactive HTML and Flash based websites, often with custom build PHP based CMS or eCommerce solutions.

Education

Commercial College, Bochum, Germany - Business Administration, 1998

Skills Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Sinatra, Rspec, Cucumber, HTML5, CSS, Canvas, JavaScript, CoffeeScript,

Backbone.js, AngularJS, Shell, ZSH, VIM, PostgreSQL, PostGIS, MongoDB, MySQL, Heroku, AWS, Ubuntu, Debian, CentOS, HTML5 Video/Audio, PHP4/5, Wordpress, Flash, ActionScript 2/3, MXML,

Flex, Flash Video, Adobe Media Server, Wowza Media Server, Adobe Photoshop

Additional Skills German (native), English (fluent), Spanish (intermediate), Adobe Premiere, Final Cut, Balsamiq

Mockups

Sample Projects Jumblzar: <a href="http://jumblzar.com">http://jumblzar.com</a> (Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, PostGIS, JavaScript, Heroku, AWS,

RSpec, Cucumber)

Thomas and Friends: <a href="http://pbskids.org/thomasandfriends/">http://pbskids.org/thomasandfriends/</a> (HTML5, Canvas, JavaScript, Ruby,

Middleman/Jekyll)

T-Venture: <a href="http://t-venture.com">http://t-venture.com</a> (Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, Adaptive Design)